Guide to the R. Philip Hanes Papers, 1928-2010 RL.00503
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
The fourth access point is company records. This section contains not only financial records of Ampersand but also information about clients and proposals. It reveals information about clients which are not included in the casebooks and the initial steps of the consulting process, even if unsuccessful subsequently.
Scope and Contents
Other aspects of Hanes's life as revealed in the collection are the interconnected interests of conservation of natural resources and outdoor recreation. His commitment to preserving the environment, especially in North Carolina, extended to both the seacoast and the mountains. He purchased most of Stone Mountain, five miles west of Roaring Gap, N.C., which became a state park. Also, Hanes was concerned as well about the preservation of the Appalachian Trail and Roan Mountain, which was threatened by commercial development. He expressed his love of the outdoors also as a hiker; hunter, especially of wild duck, pheasant, and dove; and trout fisherman.
Hanes's interest in the environment led him to serve several conservation societies as governor, director, national advisor, and committee member. These include the Nature Conservancy, the National Audubon Society, the American Land Trust, the Izaak Walton League of America, Appalachian Trail Conference, and the Appalachian Highlands Association. In addition, Hanes was a founder of the Southern Appalachian Highlands Conservancy and the North Carolina Land Heritage Trust. The Personal and Boards Series in particular reflect these interests in ecology and outdoor recreation. There are large files for the National Audubon Society and the Nature Conservancy, and to a lesser extent the Appalachian Greenway. Other related files in this series include the Izaak Walton League, the Appalachian Trail, Currituck, Shooting Clubs, Ecology, Conservation, Hunting, New River, Roan Mountain, Cane River, and Stone Mountain. There also is some information on The Nature Conservancy in the Ampersand Chronological Files Series. The North Carolina Recreation Commission has some information in the Geographic and Subject Files Series, and the National Recreation Association is represented in the Subject Files Series.
Scope and Contents
In the Subject Files Series many different topics are represented. Four major ones which have not been noted above include the National Council on the Arts, the National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities, the American Symphony Orchestra League, and Arts Management.
Scope and Contents
There are many letters of prominent persons who were involved in the arts world as artists, as patrons of the arts, or as members of advisory boards of organizations. These correspondents include Edward B. Benjamin, Ralph Burgard, Lammot duPont Copeland, Agnes De Mille, John Ehle, Nancy Hanks, Paul Hudgins, George M. Irwin, Jarold A. Kieffer, Margot Logan, W. McNeil Lowry, Charles Christopher Mark, Sam Ragan, Alvin H. Reiss, Samuel R. Rosenbaum, Michael Whitney Straight, Robert Suderburg, Alvin Toffler, Richard P. Trenbeth, Eric Walter White, and Jonathan Williams. Other correspondents, who were not chiefly artists, shared Hanes's interest in promoting the arts. There are occasional letters from North Carolina governors and other political figures including Jesse Helms, James E. Holshouser, James B. Hunt, Benjamin Everett Jordan, Joan Mondale, Daniel Killian Moore, Terry Sanford, and Robert Walter Scott. Celebrities, such as Helen Hayes and Charlton Heston, also appear in the letters. Other correspondents include John Mason Brewer, Milton Esterow, William Coffield Fields, Siebolt Henry Frieswyk, Norman Lloyd, Sir Peter Ramsbotham, John D. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, James H. Semans, Mary Duke Biddle Trent Semans, and Edward Weeks.
Names have been indexed only where both quantity and quality (research content) were present. Often the correspondence of one person in this collection is scattered throughout, rather than grouped in one series.
Unprocessed Additions (Accs. 1990-060, 1990-084, 1992-066, 1996-136, and 2004-081)
The collection includes 28 boxes from unprocessed additions, which have no boxlist or other descriptions available. These boxes are numbered by Accession number. Unprocessed additions (5479 items; dated [1950s]-2004) include correspondence, greeting cards, subject files, financial records, reports, memorabilia, photographs, videotapes, and a large poster of Hanes' family tree. Materials reflect especially Hanes' interest in the arts, conservation (particularly in western North Carolina and Virginia), and the city of Winston-Salem.
Addition: Acc. (2010-0201)
Addition includes correspondence, both incoming and outgoing, as well as appointment books, clippings, and miscellaneous materials relating to Hanes' philanthropy and community involvement in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. Prominent topics include the Hanes farm and other conservation and agricultural enterprises; his role in various arts councils and arts movements throughout the city and country, including the National Endowment for the Arts; his interactions with Wake Forest University and other academic institutions; his communications with Wachovia Bank; and other issues or movements that he supported. The majority of the materials are loosely arranged in a chronological file, dating from 1940-2010 (bulk dating from 1991-2009).
Arts -- Societies, etc.; Slides (photographs); Arts -- Publicity; Arts -- North Carolina; Arts -- Management; Arts fund raising; Photographs; Conservation of natural resources -- North Carolina; Awards in the Visual Arts; Ampersand Incorporated; Arts Council (Winston-Salem, N.C.); Burgard, Ralph; De Mille, Agnes; Associated Council of the Arts; Benjamin, Edward B., 1897-; Hanks, Nancy, 1927-1983; Hayes, Helen, 1900-; North Carolina Arts Council; National Endowment for the Arts; Reiss, Alvin H.; Hanes, R. Philip, 1926-2011; Irwin, George M.; Hanes, R. Philip, 1926-2011; Hunt, James B., 1937-; Moore, Daniel Killian, 1906-; Jargon Society; Williams, Jonathan, 1929-; Suderburg, Robert; North Carolina School of the Arts; Semans, James H.; Sanford, Terry; Stevens, Roger L.; Southeastern Center for Contemporary Art
- Geographic Series, 1928-1983, undated
  Scope and Contents note
  Chiefly correspondence to and from Hanes, and printed material, such as brochures, booklets, leaflets, pamphlets, newsletters, and programs. Also included are photographs, reports and annual reports, clippings, surveys, membership lists, and press releases. Organized alphabetically by geographic area, first by state, then city. The small amount of material for various foreign countries follows the U.S. folders.
  - Alabama, 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, Birmingham, 1959-1968 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, Birmingham: Arts Council Survey, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, Birmingham: Festivals, 1962-1967 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, Huntsville, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Alabama, Huntsville: Arts Council, 1961-1969, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Alabama, Mobile: Arts Council, 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Alaska, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, Phoenix: Arts Council, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, Phoenix: Festivals, Surveys, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Arizona, Tucson: Festivals, Special Ideas, 1959-1969 (Box 1)
  - Arkansas: Festivals, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
  - Arkansas, Little Rock: Arts Council, Center, 1957-1969 (Box 2)
  - Arkansas University: Opera Workshop, Mar.- Sept., 1961 (Box 2)
  - California, 1961-1968(2 folders) (Box 2)
  - California: Arts Commission, 1963-1966 and undated, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - California: Festivals, Surveys, 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - California, Los Angeles, 1961-1970 (Box 2)
  - California, Los Angeles: County Music Competition, Mar.-June 1962 (Box 2)
  - California, Los Angeles: Galleries, Museums, Surveys, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
  - California, Los Angeles: Greek Theater Association 1960-1961 (Box 3)
  - California, Los Angeles: Music Center, 1964-1965 and undated, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - California, Los Angeles: Schools, Festivals, 1961-1965 (Box 3)
  - California, Orange County Council of Arts, Festivals, 1963-1969 (Box 3)
  - California, San Francisco Bay, 1961-1969 (Box 3)
  - California, San Francisco: Bohemia Club, 1968 (Box 3)
  - California, San Francisco Bay, Festivals, Surveys, Special Ideas, Mar. 1961-Jan. 1962 (Box 3)
  - California, San Francisco: Oracle, Dec. 1966- Mar. 1967 (Box 3)
  - California, San Francisco: Oracle, Oct. 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - California, Santa Clara Co: Surveys, Feb., 1961-Sept., 1961 (Box 4)
  - California University: Festivals, Special Ideas, Dec. 1961-Aug. 1963 (Box 4)
  - Colorado Arts Council: Festivals, Schools, Mar. 1961-June 1967 (Box 4)
  - Colorado, Aspen: Festivals, Schools, Jan. 1962-June 1969 (Box 4)
  - Colorado, Colorado Springs: Fine Arts Center, Surveys, Oct.-Dec. 1961 (Box 4)
  - Colorado, Denver-Univ.: Surveys, Festivals, Nov. 1961-June 1969 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut, March 1961-Sept. 1965 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut: Arts Commission, 1963-Apr. 1968 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut, Hartford: Coordinating Council for Arts Surveys, 1960-1969 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut, New Canaan: Silvermine Guild of Artists, School of Art, Oct. 1960-July 1963 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut, New Haven: Surveys, Nov. 1960- Aug. 1965 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut, Stratford: Festivals, 1961-1965 (Box 4)
  - Connecticut, Westport, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Connecticut, Westport: Famous Artists Schools, Inc., Oct. 1962-Jan. 1964 (Box 5)
  - Connecticut, Westport: Famous Artists Schools Annual Report, 1963-1969(2 boxes) (Box 5)
  - Delaware, Dec. 1961-Feb. 1967 (Box 5)
  - Florida, 1961-1967 (Box 5)
  - Florida: Arts Council, Summary Report, Dec. 1963-Dec. 1966(2 boxes) (Box 5)
  - Florida: Festivals, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Florida, Coral Gables: U-Miami-Surveys, 1960-1963 (Box 5)
  - Florida, Ft. Lauderdale: Arts Council, March 1960-1965 (Box 5)
  - Florida, Jacksonville: Surveys, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Florida, Pensacola: Art Center Surveys, July 1958-May 1963 (Box 6)
  - Georgia: Art Commission, June 1960-April 1968 (Box 6)
  - Georgia, Athens: University of Georgia, Oct. 1962- Apr. 1968 (Box 6)
  - Georgia, Atlanta, 1953-1969 (Box 6)
  - Georgia, Atlanta: Festival, Art Center, Special Ideas, 1957-1969 and undated(2 boxes) (Box 6)
  - Georgia, Savannah, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Hawaii, Honolulu: Surveys, 1961-Oct 1967 (Box 6)
  - Idaho: Commission on Arts/Humanities, undated (Box 6)
  - Illinois, Mar. 1961-Mar. 1970 and undated (Box 6)
  - Illinois, Chicago: Art Institute, 1958-1966. (Box 6)
  - Illinois, Chicago: Festival, Jan. 1957-Feb. 1969 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Chicago: Music, July 1956-Jan. 1964 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Godfrey: Monticello College, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Peoria: Arts and Sciences Federation, 1959-1963 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Quincy: Festivals, Society of Fine Arts, Nov. 1958-Jan. 1966 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Quincy: Galleries, Museums, Mar. 1960-1961 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Quincy: Music, Theatre, Apr. 1960- Feb. 1965 (Box 7)
  - Illinois, Springfield: Surveys, undated (Box 7)
  - Illinois, University of: Festival, Apr. 1962- June 1968 (Box 7)
  - Indiana, March 1961-January 1968 and undated(2 boxes) (Box 7)
  - Indiana: Schools, September 1961-April 1964 (Box 7)
  - Indiana, Evansville: Surveys, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Indiana, Fort Wayne: Festival, Fine Arts Foundation, May 1958-February 1966 (Box 7)
  - Indiana, Indianapolis, 1961-1967 (Box 8)
  - Iowa, March 1960-1966 (Box 8)
  - Iowa, Devenport, January 1959-February 1962 (Box 8)
  - Iowa, Sioux City, 1961-1963 (Box 8)
  - Iowa, Waterloo: Civic Foundation, Recreation Center, Community, 1959-1961 (Box 8)
  - Kansas, May 25, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Kansas, Lindsborg: Bethany College, Nov. 1960- Apr. 1963 (Box 8)
  - Kansas, Wichita University: Festival, Sept. 1958- Oct. 1966 (Box 8)
  - Kentucky, 1965-1968 (Box 8)
  - Kentucky, Danville: Art Colony, 1958-1966 (Box 8)
  - Kentucky, Louisville: Surveys, Special Ideas (Box 8)
  - Louisville Fund, Oct. 1955-Aug. 1967 (Box 8)
  - Louisiana: Surveys, 1963-1969 (Box 8)
  - Louisiana, New Orleans, 1961-1966 (Box 8)
  - Louisiana, New Orleans: Cultural Attractions Fund, 1959-1961 (Box 8)
  - Maine: Commission on Arts and Humanities, 1966-1968 (Box 8)
  - Maine: Schools and Surveys, 1961-1967 (Box 9)
  - Maine, Portland: Music, 1960-1965 (Box 9)
  - Maine, Portland: Surveys, Galleries and Museums, 1963-1965 (Box 9)
  - Maryland: Schools, Arts Council, 1961-1967 (Box 9)
  - Maryland, Baltimore: Surveys, Schools and Galleries, 1960-1966 (Box 9)
  - Maryland, Montgomery Co.: Arts Center, Schools, 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts: Schools and Festivals, 1961-1970(2 boxes) (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts, Berkshire Co.: Festival, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts, Boston: Festival, Surveys, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts, Pittsfield: Arts Center, Southern Mountain Association, 1957-1962 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts, Springfield, 1961-1963 (Box 9)
  - Massachusetts, Worcester: Special Ideas, Festival, 1951-1968 (Box 10)
  - Michigan, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Michigan: Festivals, Surveys, Arts Council, 1961-1968 (Box 10)
  - Michigan: Michigan Cultural Commission, 1960-1968(2 boxes) (Box 10)
  - Michigan, Detroit, 1961-1965 (Box 10)
  - Michigan, Detroit: Archives of American Art, 1960-1964 (Box 10)
  - Michigan, Detroit: Institute of Arts, Detroit Adventure, 1959-1964 (Box 10)
  - Michigan, Detroit: Music, 1957-1963 (Box 10)
  - Michigan, Flint: College, Special Ideas and Cultural Development, Inc., 1959-1963 (Box 10)
  - Michigan, Interlochen: National Music Camp, 1951-1970 (Box 11)
  - Michigan, Rochester: Oakland University, 1964-1966 (Box 11)
  - Michigan, Rochester: Oakland University, 1968 and undated (Box 11)
  - Michigan, Saginaw: Arts Council, 1961-1963 (Box 11)
  - Michigan: University of Michigan, 1961-1965 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota: State Arts Council, 1961-1969 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota: University of Minnesota, 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota, Minneapolis, July-August 1962 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota, Minneapolis: Institute of Arts, Society of Fine Arts, March-October 1962 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota, Minneapolis: Music, Surveys, 1961-1964 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota, Minneapolis: Theater, 1963-1965 (Box 11)
  - Minnesota, St. Paul, 1960-1966 (Box 12)
  - Minnesota, St. Paul: Council of Arts and Science, 1959-1968 (Box 12)
  - Mississippi, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
  - Missouri: Council on the Arts, 1962-1965 and undated, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Missouri: Universities, 1958-1963 (Box 12)
  - Missouri, Kansas City, 1958-1967 (Box 12)
  - Missouri, St. Louis, 1961-1966 (Box 12)
  - Missouri, St. Louis: Arts Council, 1960-1968 (Box 12)
  - Missouri, St. Louis: Arts Council Calendars, 1966 and undated (Box 12)
  - Missouri, St. Louis: Arts Council, Surveys, 1962-1963 and undated, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Montana, 1961-1970 (Box 13)
  - Nebraska: Schools, 1963-1968 (Box 13)
  - Nebraska: Cultural Resources Council, 1963-1965 (Box 13)
  - Nevada: Festival, undated (Box 13)
  - New Hampshire: Arts Council, 1961-1965 (Box 13)
  - New Hampshire: School, Festival, 1961-1965 (Box 13)
  - New Jersey: Special Ideas, Surveys, 1961-1964 (Box 13)
  - New Jersey: State Cultural Center, Community, 1963-1966 (Box 13)
  - New Jersey: Universities, Schools, 1961-1963 (Box 14)
  - New Jersey, Newark: Greater Newark Development Council, Jan.-Feb. 1962 (Box 14)
  - New Mexico, 1959-1969 (Box 14)
  - New Mexico: Arts Commission, 1965-1968 (Box 14)
  - New York, 1964-1969 and undated (Box 14)
  - New York: State Council on the Arts, 1960-1970 and undated, 3 folders (Box 14)
  - New York: State Concil on the Arts, Arrangements, Touring Groups, Mechanics, 1963-1969 (Box 14)
  - New York: Surveys, Festival, Art Centers, Schools, 1961-1965 (Box 14)
  - New York: Surveys, Festival, Art Centers, Schools, 1961-1966 and undated, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - New York, Binghamton: Roberson Center, 1961-1966 and undated, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - New York, Buffalo: Art Council, Festival, Special Ideas, 1961-1968 (Box 15)
  - New York, Chautauqua:Schools, 1961-1965 (Box 15)
  - New York, Long Island: Schools, Festivals, Arts Centers and Councils, 1961-1965 (Box 15)
  - New York, Middletown: Arts Council, 1961-1966 (Box 15)
  - New York, New York City, 1961-1969 (Box 15)
  - New York, New York City: Bankers Trust Company, 1962 and undated (Box 15)
  - New York, New York City: Festival, 1961-1969 and n.d, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Galleries, Museums, 1965-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Brochures, Programs, 1959-1968 and undated, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Clippings, Misc., 1958-1968 (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Correspondence, 1958-1970 (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Design, Construction, Acoustics, 1958-1963 (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Festival, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Finance, 1962-1966 (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Metro- politan Opera, 1961-1966 and undated, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Lincoln Center, Student Program, 1961-1968 (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Music and Dance, 1961-1968 (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Music and Dance, American Ballet Theatre, 1965-1968 (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Office of Cultural Affairs, 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Schools, 1960-1965 and undated (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Surveys, Galleries, Museums, etc., 1960-1965 (Box 17)
  - New York, New York City: Theater, 1962-1969 (Box 18)
  - New York, Rensslaer Co.: Council for the Arts, 1965 (Box 18)
  - New York, Rochester: Surveys, Festival, Schools, 1962-1964 (Box 18)
  - New York, Rockland Co.: The Lively Arts of Rockland County, 1959-1963 (Box 18)
  - New York, Rome: Council on History/Arts, 1965 (Box 18)
  - New York, Saratoga Springs: Performing Arts Center, 1961-1964 (Box 18)
  - New York, Syracuse: Schools, Surveys, Council Cultural Agencies, 1961-1963 (Box 18)
  - New York, Westchester Co.: Arts Center, Festival, 1961-1967 and undated, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - North Carolina, 1958-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - North Carolina: The Arts Council of Winston-Salem, 1963-1964 (Box 18)
  - North Carolina: Associated Artists of NC, 1962-1966 (Box 18)
  - North Carolina: Conference on Responsibility for Athletic Quality (Box 19)
  - North Carolina: Correspondence and Clippings, 1960-1970 (Box 19)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council, 1964-1969 and undated, 6 folders (Box 19)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council--Arts in North Carolina, 1967 (Box 19)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council--Arts Resources Study, November, 1966 and undated (Box 19)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council--Arts Resources Study, March 1967 (Box 19)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council--Committee Reports, 1961-1966 (Box 20)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council Correspondence, Mar. 1963-Mar. 1970, 7 folders (Box 20)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council--Panel Reports, 1965 (Box 20)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Arts Council--The State of the Arts, 1969 (Box 20)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Collectors, 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Recreation Commission, 1963-1966 and undated, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: North Carolina Recreation Commission Correspondence, 1961-1966 (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: The North Carolina State Art Society, 1962-1966 and undated, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: The North Carolina Symphony, 1960-1970 and undated (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: Rockefeller Bros. Fund--State Study, 1963 (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: Stone Mountain Park, Jan. 1968- July 1968 (Box 21)
  - North Carolina: Triangle Repertory Theatre, 1966 (Box 22)
  - North Carolina: Tri-States Arts Council, Feb. 1960-May, 1966 and undated, 4 folders (Box 22)
  - North Carolina: Tri-States Arts Council--Survey, Conference, June-Sept. 1959 (Box 22)
  - North Carolina: Tri-States Arts Council--Survey, Conference, Oct.-Nov. 1959 and undated (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Albemarle Area: Development, Arts Council, 1964-1968 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Asheville: Festival, Civic Arts Center, 1960-1968 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Black Mountain, 1966-67 and undated, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Brevard: Brevard Music Center, 1959-1969, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Burlington, 1966 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Carteret County, 1968 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Chapel Hill: Festival, 1962-1967 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Chapel Hill: UNC-Institute of Outdoor Drama, 1963-1966 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Charlotte: Arts Council, 1955-1970 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Durham: Allied Arts Surveys, 1959-1969 (Box 23)
  - North Carolina, Durham: Learning Institute of NC, 1965-1967 (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Durham: Triangle Repertory Theatre, 1965-1967, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Fayetteville: NC State Ballet Company, 1960-1969 (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Gastonia: Arts Council, 1965 (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Greensboro: Arts Council, 1963-1970 and undated, 3 folders (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Greensboro: Festival, Guilford Musical Arts Center, 1954-1967 (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Greensboro: Richardson Foundation, 1965 (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Greenville: Art Center, East Carolina University, 1962-1966 (Box 24)
  - North Carolina, Greenville: Art Center, East Carolina University, 1966-1968 and undated (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Hickory: Arts Council, 1961-1965 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, High Point: Arts Council, 1962-1968 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Jugtown, 1968-1969 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Kinston: Arts Council, Festival, 1965-1967 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Louisburg, 1967 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Misenheimer, 1963 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Penland: Jonathan Williams, 1967-1970, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Penland: Paul Hudgins, 1966- Apr.-June, 1968 (Box 25)
  - North Carolina, Penland: Paul Hudgins, 1968-June 27, 1969 and undated (Box 26)
  - North Carolina, Penland: Penland School of Crafts, 1962-1970, and undated, 4 folders (Box 26)
  - North Carolina, Pilot Mountain: Preservation and Park Committee, 1967 (Box 26)
  - North Carolina, Raleigh: Arts Council, 1959-1969 (Box 26)
  - North Carolina, Raleigh: National Opera Company, 1959-1969 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Raleigh: Scrapbook, 1953-1969 and undated (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Raleigh: NC Museum of Art, 1958-1983 and undated (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Raleigh: NC Museum of Art, Artist's Exhibition, 1955-1962 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Raleigh: NC Museum of Art, Calendars, 1960-1968 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Rocky Mount: Arts Center, 1960-1968 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Rutherfordton: 1968 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Statesville, 1960-1964 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Surry County: Arts Council, and undated (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Sylva: Smokey Mountain Cultural Arts Development, 1968-1969 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Wilmington, 1961-1968 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem, 1928-1969 and undated, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Advancement School, 1964-1967 (Box 27)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Arts Council, 1951-1969 and undated, 3 folders (Box 28)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Arts Council--Clippings, 1956-1967 (Box 28)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Arts Council--Correspondence, 1958-1970, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Arts Council Reports, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Arts and Crafts Association, 1960-1968 (Box 28)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Arts in Winston -Salem, 1966-1967 (Box 28)
  - North Carolina, Winston-Salem: Babcock Foundation, 1965-1969 (Box 29)